<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gainclone on Adam Piekarski</title>
    <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/tags/gainclone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gainclone on Adam Piekarski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fatcookies.github.io/tags/gainclone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dual mono LM3886 chip amp</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp2/</guid>
      <description>My second endeavour into building an audio amplifier
Round Two. Link to heading Background Link to heading After successfully building a LM3886 amplifier a couple of years ago, I decided it was time to build another one, be a bit ambitious with it and create something with a bit more oomfph. My previous attempt is still very capable, but is now starting to fall to bits because I didn&amp;rsquo;t own appropriate tools to produce a solid enclosure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LM3886 Chip Amp (Gainclone)</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp/</guid>
      <description>A high-power audio amplifier using the infamous LM3886 chip
Amplify Now. Link to heading Background Link to heading The original Gaincard amplifier by 47 Laboratory, released in 1999, defied all the elders&amp;rsquo; wisdom of amplifier construction. Discrete transitors were ditched and a Texas Instruments LM3875 operation-amplifier sat in the heart of it all - you can read more about it here.
Shortly after the Gaincard was released, the DIY community embraced its controversial design and started creating clones, leading to the portmantau Gainclone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
