<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Piekarski</title>
    <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Piekarski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fatcookies.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>35mm Pinhole Camera</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/camera/</guid>
      <description>How I made it: Link to heading The humble beginnings Link to heading I picked up a couple of baking trays for the total price of 3 quid - very good value I must say!
Initial body cut Link to heading You can cut through these trays with a good pair of scissors.
Marking out the pinhole Link to heading My very shoddy metalwork Link to heading The task of creating a hole in the middle of a sheet of aluminium without the aid of power tools was rather difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boombox</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/boombox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/boombox/</guid>
      <description>My take on creating a boombox - a 10kg booming monster
How I made it: Link to heading Front design in SketchUp Link to heading This is my initial idea of two full range drivers and one &amp;ldquo;subwoofer&amp;rdquo; driver to deliver the bass.
I was a little enthusiastic with the dimensions and the finished product is a lot smaller than this.
Back design in SketchUp Link to heading Three chambers - one for each speaker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceefax 2015</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/ceefax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/ceefax/</guid>
      <description>A modern twist to an old favourite
Take me back to 1974 Link to heading Now. Link to heading The idea Link to heading Since the launch of Ceefax, over 40 years ago, it has gifted a generation before the internet with on-demand, up-to-date news from the comfort of sofa&amp;rsquo;s across the country. Despite being born just before the big internet boom, Ceefax still played a part of my childhood so naturally I was devestated when it ceased to broadcast along with analog terrestrial television.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DJ Controller</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/dj/</guid>
      <description>A very compact Arduino based DJ Controller
How I made it: Link to heading The enclosure Link to heading I had a couple of these nuts and bolts storage boxes lying around and they seemed to be the perfect size for this tiny beast.
Drilling out the component holes Link to heading Drilled out three different types of holes for the potentiometers, push buttons and LED&amp;rsquo;s. A bonus hole right at the back for the mini-USB port required to hook the thing up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual mono LM3886 chip amp</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp2/</guid>
      <description>My second endeavour into building an audio amplifier
Round Two. Link to heading Background Link to heading After successfully building a LM3886 amplifier a couple of years ago, I decided it was time to build another one, be a bit ambitious with it and create something with a bit more oomfph. My previous attempt is still very capable, but is now starting to fall to bits because I didn&amp;rsquo;t own appropriate tools to produce a solid enclosure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eardentity</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/eardentity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/eardentity/</guid>
      <description>An Android ear identification app
Using the ear as a biometric Link to heading Much of society strives to construct an unique and individual personality and some radically change their physical appearance so choosing a robust biometric to identify a human can be a challenge. Finger tips, iris, gait, face among others have been tried, tested and successfully rolled out - each with their own advantages and disadvantages.
In recent years the ear has emerged as a potentially useful biometric to suppliment existing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Teapot Spammer</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/teapot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/teapot/</guid>
      <description>What is this? Link to heading A marvellous chrome extension which punishes your victims Facebook statuses if they go afk for too long!
The source code for this extension and download can be found on my Github
What does it do? Link to heading Upon installing the extension onto your victim&amp;rsquo;s computer, it will silently run in the background and detect if they are inactive from their computer for more than four minutes (this can be changed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LM3886 Chip Amp (Gainclone)</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/amp/</guid>
      <description>A high-power audio amplifier using the infamous LM3886 chip
Amplify Now. Link to heading Background Link to heading The original Gaincard amplifier by 47 Laboratory, released in 1999, defied all the elders&amp;rsquo; wisdom of amplifier construction. Discrete transitors were ditched and a Texas Instruments LM3875 operation-amplifier sat in the heart of it all - you can read more about it here.
Shortly after the Gaincard was released, the DIY community embraced its controversial design and started creating clones, leading to the portmantau Gainclone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piggy Fly</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/piggy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/piggy/</guid>
      <description>A fast-paced casual Android game cough Flappy Bird clone cough
When will pigs fly? Now. Link to heading The backdrop Link to heading During the explosion of the Flappy Bird frenzy and consequent demise, I decided to make a clone. The famous adynaton became a reality: Piggy Fly was born.
Gameplay Link to heading There&amp;rsquo;s not much to say here - you touch the screen; the pig flies. The physics is even more annoying than Flappy Bird&amp;rsquo;s, so I wish you the best of luck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiFi Kettle</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/wifi-kettle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/projects/wifi-kettle/</guid>
      <description>After being inspired by the rather novel iKettle, I decided I could create my own WiFi enable kettle as a little project!
How I made it: Link to heading The enclosure Link to heading One of the last components I actually bought - it&amp;rsquo;s just a small power supply unit enclosure I picked up for a couple of quid from Maplin.
Bottom side of the enclosure Link to heading I have many Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s lying around the house, I believe the one pictured is the first Model B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a recent Computer Science graduate from the University of Southampton, graduating with a First class honours in MEng Computer Science.
I now work as an Embedded Software Engineer at Qualcomm in Cambrdige, United Kingdom.
I enjoy developing solutions for standard desktop applications, mobile and low-level hardware programming - particularly audio orientated projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/posts/</guid>
      <description>To be continued &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://fatcookies.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fatcookies.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description> Github Twitter LinkedIn </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
